<document>
    <page page="1">
        <title>BUDDHISM IN VIETNAM MONTHLY JOURNAL</title>
        <subtitle>Translation Compilation of Chinese Texts</subtitle>
        <issue_number>24</issue_number>
        <release_date>August 15th, Year of the Dog (Mậu Tuất)</release_date>
        <publisher>Vietnamese Buddhist Association Publishing</publisher>
    </page>
    <page page="2">
        <title>TABLE OF CONTENTS</title>
        <section>
            <title>PREFACE</title>
            <content>Buddhism in Vietnam Monthly Turns Two</content>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>FEATURES</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>THE INDESTRUCTIBLE POWER OF THE SUBCONSCIOUS</title>
            <author>Jadigh Kasyapa</author>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Master Huyền Trang Journeys to India for the Sutras (Continued)</title>
            <author>Dương Đình Phúc</author>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>QUESTIONS - PHUONG BOI</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Joy in the Dharma Life</title>
            <description>(Short story with honorable mention)</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>MATERIALS ON THE BUDDHIST FAMILY</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>SEARCHING FOR CHÂU-LÍ</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>The Buddhist Nun Marguerite La Fuente Has Passed Away</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>NEWS</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Results of the Editorial Office Competition</title>
            <author>Minh-Trâm</author>
        </section>
        <author>Nguyễn Khắc Từ</author>
        <author>Nguyễn-Đức-Tương</author>
        <organization>P.G.V.N.</organization>
    </page>
    <page page="3">
        <separator>_</separator>
    </page>
    <page page="4">
        <title>BUDDHISM IN VIETNAM TURNS TWO</title>
        <p>With this 24th issue, the Buddhism in Vietnam Monthly Journal has reached its second
            anniversary. Born amidst financial difficulties within its community and the broader
            economic influence, Buddhism in Vietnam tasted the "bitter and sweet" from its infancy.
            Its journey was unexpectedly challenging! Being the intellectual offspring of the
            Vietnamese Buddhist General Association, born at a Buddhist Conference, and under the
            auspices of six senior collectives from the Central, South, and North regions, it was
            thought that it would have a prosperous life. However, perhaps fate was challenging, and
            its spiritual father often fell ill, while the elder collectives were perpetually busy
            with their own lives and had little time to care for it.</p>
        <p>Yet, having the honor of being the offspring of the Vietnamese Buddhist General
            Association and the protégé of the Buddhist collectives from three regions, it had to
            soon learn independence and strive to build its life, not to shame its father and
            brothers. Although still young, it understood its important mission was to protect and
            support its frail father, call for tight unity among its brethren, and raise the flag of <i>Chánh
            Pháp</i>[1], expressing the earnest and true voice of the Buddha.</p>
        <footer>PHẬT-GIÁO VIỆT NAM</footer>
    </page>
    <page page="5">
        <p>In its struggle to live and fulfill its mission, it encountered numerous obstacles but
            also gleaned valuable experiences, learning who were friends and who were not,
            recognizing who were fellow believers and who were insincere. Most encouraging is that
            the number of supporters of its cause grew daily, along with its readership.</p>
        <p>These accomplishments fueled enthusiasm and determination, so stepping into its third
            year, Buddhism in Vietnam Monthly Journal vows to endeavor in realizing its set goals,
            improving content and form to meet the historical stages of Vietnamese Buddhism,
            aligning with the capacities and aspirations of its readers. Regarding Buddhist
            scriptures, the journal will seek to develop teachings that can address human anxieties
            and aspirations in the latter half of the 20th century, thoughts that might contribute
            to building the spiritual life of Vietnamese people currently swayed by foreign
            ideologies.</p>
        <p>Regarding culture and arts, the journal will broaden its scope, dedicating more pages to
            welcoming new writers and supporting budding talents sympathetic to Buddhism.</p>
        <p>Moreover, the journal will allocate a section about the Buddhist family, an educational
            organization for young Buddhists, currently flourishing but lacking materials and
            foundational theories as its basic structure. In this section, the journal joyfully
            accepts all cultural and creative contributions from all Buddhist family members.</p>
        <p>In conclusion, we wish to highlight an important point and draw the reader's attention
            to…</p>
    </page>
    <page page="6">
        <p>Buddhism, born with the mission of promoting the unified spirit of Buddhism, this monthly
            journal vows to be a vanguard in the front line of Buddhist unity and cohesion, to break
            all divisive thoughts and actions, to welcome goodwill and actions of Buddhist unity.
            From the next issue, we will talk extensively about this topic, exposing all facets,
            finding causes for the stagnation of Buddhist unity, proposing remedial methods, and
            devising a concrete and practical program to lead to a congress of delegates from six
            Buddhist collectives, similar to the 51 delegate national congress at Từ Đàm in 1951.</p>
        <p>To prepare for such a Congress, Buddhism in Vietnam Monthly Journal welcomes all reader
            opinions and especially those from authorities in the Buddhist collectives. The journal
            will be delighted to serve as a free forum for all constructive opinions towards real
            Buddhist unity in Vietnam.</p>
        <signature>P. G. V. N.</signature>
        <footer>PHẬT-GIÁO VIỆT-NAM</footer>
    </page>
    <page page="7">
        <title>THE INDESTRUCTIBLE POWER OF THE SUBCONSCIOUS</title>
        <author>By Jadigh Kasyapa</author>
        <translator>Translated by Tuệ Uyên</translator>
        <p>We are always aware of one thing and forget another. As we walk down the street and meet
            someone, we recognize them. After walking a bit further, we forget them, and their image
            fades in our consciousness. Another object, like a car or a house, catches our
            attention, and we see and recognize it. As we walk further, we forget again, the image
            of the car or house is erased just like before, making way for new images.</p>
        <p>Therefore, our consciousness is aware of one object and forgets another, and so it
            continues endlessly. From the moment we are born, this stream of direct perception and
            forgetting flows uninterrupted like a stream.</p>
        <p>Even when we are not receiving external impressions, like when we are asleep, this stream
            continues, as old impressions emerge and disappear continuously in our consciousness.
            However, not all objects are forgotten the same way. Something that attracts our
            attention strongly and causes a strong sensation is forgotten more slowly because its
            impact lingers in the mind for a somewhat longer time.</p>
        <footer>PHẬT GIÁO VIỆT NAM</footer>
    </page>
    <page page="8">
        <p>In contrast, something that does not catch our attention is forgotten immediately after
            being perceived. If, while walking, we encounter an elephant, the image of the elephant
            remains long in our mind, and as we walk, we keep remembering the elephant we just met,
            walking a long distance without its image fading from our mind. If we meet an ordinary
            person with nothing special, after just a few steps, we forget them immediately.</p>
        <p>However, what we forget is not entirely lost or erased. Whether forgotten quickly or
            slowly, what we have known remains in our consciousness. Forgetting merely means storing
            it in the subconscious. Our consciousness is a vast repository where all the thoughts
            and images we have experienced are carefully stored. Everything we have thought of,
            sensed, or done is still there.</p>
        <p>We can make these thoughts and images reappear in our consciousness if we wish.
            Therefore, our consciousness consists of two parts: <ol>
                <li>Immediate perception and sensation, active in the present.</li>
                <li>The storage of all thoughts and sensations we have forgotten.</li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>Psychologists call the first function the consciousness and the second the subconscious.</p>
        <p>It is generally believed that what we remember persists and operates in the
            consciousness, while what we forget falls into the subconscious, lying dormant or being
            destroyed there. This is a misconception. In actuality, what is in the subconscious is
            also active and struggling to return to consciousness; whenever a favorable condition
            arises, it can manifest in consciousness immediately. Bergson stated: All that we feel,
            search for, and desire since childhood still remains. Those elements are trying to
            return to the present, trying to merge with the present to challenge the fortress of
            consciousness that constantly seeks to prevent them from emerging.</p>
        <p>The Buddha also taught similarly: The current personality of a person is the result of
            all they have done, felt, and thought since time immemorial.</p>
        <footer>PHẬT GIÁO VIỆT NAM</footer>
    </page>
    <page page="9">
        <p>The personality of a thief does not resemble that of a saint because, in the past, these
            two individuals acted and thought differently. What existed in the past is not
            destroyed; it still exists in the present. Our past actions and thoughts always shadow
            us, "just like the earth trails the steps of the oxen pulling the cart, or the shadow
            follows the form."</p>
        <p>Therefore, the present person is exactly crafted by the past person, a faithful
            reflection of the past actions and thoughts stored in their consciousness. The
            characteristics of past actions and thoughts determine the person's characteristics at
            present. This precisely is the life, the individuality of a person. We create ourselves.</p>
        <p>Beyond our consciousness (comprising consciousness and subconscious), there is no other
            element such as a soul or a spirit. We are precisely our consciousness. A pure person is
            because their consciousness is filled with pure thoughts and images. If the
            consciousness is filled with vile and sinful thoughts, the person is impure and tainted.</p>
        <p>However, someone might doubt: If all our experiences, even the smallest details, are
            stored in the subconscious, why can we only remember most of these experiences, only
            recalling a few?</p>
        <p>This ability is due to the strength or weakness of the consciousness, which allows us to
            remember more or less. Strong consciousness can easily evoke images from the
            subconscious. A person practicing meditation can quiet the consciousness, thereby
            granting it strong power to swiftly rekindle these images. The consciousness of average
            people is always restless, thus weaker in power.</p>
        <p>The more concentrated and calm the consciousness, the stronger its ability to interact
            with the subconscious. The Buddha utilized the full power of consciousness, able to
            recall events from countless past lives. Thus, there is nothing extraordinary. All
            things are stored in the subconscious, and with concentrated, potent consciousness, one
            can recollect it all.</p>
        <p>The subconscious is not something that begins when we are born. It has existed for time
            immemorial, and it becomes richer each day. Every image, sound, or thought that enters
            the subconscious is preserved indefinitely, never lost.</p>
        <additional_section>
            <heading>What is the Path of Truth?</heading>
            <content>The Path of Truth is the Noble Eightfold Path. (It is the path that is right) <ol>
                    <li>Right View (correct understanding and thought).</li>
                    <li>Right Intention (correct thinking).</li>
                    <li>Right Speech (correct speech).</li>
                    <li>Right Action (correct conduct).</li>
                    <li>Right Livelihood (correct occupation).</li>
                    <li>Right Effort.</li>
                    <li>Right Mindfulness (correct recollection).</li>
                    <li>Right Concentration.</li>
                </ol> These eight principles are
                truly the path of the sages. </content>
        </additional_section>
        <footer>PHẬT GIÁO VIỆT NAM</footer>
    </page>
    <page page="10">
        <title>MASTER HUYỀN TRANG'S</title>
        <subtitle>JOURNEY TO INDIA FOR THE BUDDHIST SUTRAS</subtitle>
        <original_text>Original Chinese Text by DƯƠNG ĐÌNH PHÚC</original_text>
        <translator>Translated by Nông Sơn</translator>
        <continuation>(Continued from the previous issue)</continuation>
        <p>That day, Master Huyền Trang, along with Thạch Bàn-Đà, set forth, reaching the side of
            the Qua-Lô river by the third watch. From a distance, they could see the Ngọc Môn Pass,
            about 10 miles from the gate. The two riverbanks were approximately one meter apart, and
            on the river's edge, there were several straight poplar trees. The two of them cut down
            the trees to build a bridge, spread grass, and piled sand on top to cross. Both man and
            horse crossed the river safely and sat together on the grass to rest.</p>
        <p>As morning approached, Thạch Bàn-Đà suddenly drew a knife and hesitated before Master
            Huyền Trang. Recognizing his burgeoning treacherous intent, Master Huyền Trang remained
            unafraid, sitting upright without standing and glaring directly at him. The treacherous
            man eventually dropped the knife, saying to the Master: "As your disciple, I realize
            that on this journey there are no available resources, only near the five Watch Towers
            are there grass and water. If we are discovered, our lives would be forfeit. It would be
            better to return." Master Huyền Trang resolutely remained silent, permitting only him to
            return to Qua Châu. Yet, he hesitated to leave, finally asking, "If you are caught and
            reveal my real name, what will become of my family?" Master Huyền Trang solemnly swore
            under the sky: "You may rest easy, even if I am captured and my body is dismembered, I
            will never reveal your name." Thạch Bàn-Đà, finally reassured, rode his horse eastward
            to return.</p>
        <footer>PHẬT GIÁO VIỆT NAM</footer>
    </page>
</document>
<footnotes>
    <footnote number="1"><i>Chánh Pháp</i> (正法) refers to the true teachings or correct law, often
        associated with the genuine teachings of the Buddha.</footnote>
</footnotes>