<document>
  <page page="1">
    <title></title>
    <author>Editor: Tâm Dịch Thuật</author>
    <footer>Issue 24, August 15th, <i>Mậu Tuất</i><footnote number="1">[1]</footnote>. Published by
      Hội Phật Giáo Việt Nam.</footer>
    <footnotes>
      <footnote number="1">The year Mậu Tuất corresponds to 1958 in the Gregorian calendar.</footnote>
    </footnotes>
  </page>
  <page page="2">
    <title>TABLE OF CONTENTS</title>
    <li><b></b>: Celebrating Two Years</li>
    <li>
      <b>P.G.V.N.</b>
    </li>
    <li><b>The Indomitable Power of the Subconscious</b> by Jadigh Kasyapa</li>
    <li><b>Master Huyền-Trang Travels to India to Seek the Sutras (Continued)</b> by Dương-đình-Phúc</li>
    <li>
      <b>Questions - Phương Bối</b>
    </li>
    <li><b>Joy of Dharma Life</b> (Award-Winning Short Story)</li>
    <li>
      <b>Materials for Buddhist Families</b>
    </li>
    <li>
      <b>In Search of Châu-lí</b>
    </li>
    <li>
      <b>Buddhist Nun Marguerite La Fuente Passes Away</b>
    </li>
    <li>
      <b>News</b>
    </li>
    <li>
      <b>Results of the Editorial Group's Recreational Contest</b>
    </li>
    <footer>Contributions by Minh-Trâm, Nguyễn Khắc Từ, Nguyễn-đức-Tương, and P.G.V.N.</footer>
  </page>
  <page page="4">
    <title>BUDDHISM IN VIETNAM TURNS TWO</title>
    <p>With this 24th issue, has reached its second anniversary. Born
      amidst financial difficulties within the organization and influenced by the general economy,
      the journal has tasted hardship right from its infancy. No one anticipated that its life would
      be this difficult! As an intellectual offspring of the Vietnamese General Buddhist
      Association, born during the Buddhist Conference, supported by six elder groups from Central,
      South, and North, everyone quietly hoped it would have a prosperous life. However, due to its
      challenging fate, its spiritual father often fell ill, and the elder supporters were always
      busy with their lives, rarely having the opportunity to care for it.</p>
    <p>Yet, being honored as the offspring of the Vietnamese General Buddhist Association, and the
      protégé of elder Buddhist groups from three regions, it must quickly become self-reliant,
      striving to build its life without bringing shame to its father and brothers. Although still
      young, it has realized its important mission, which is to protect and support its ailing
      father, to call for tight-knit unity among siblings of one bloodline and ideal, to raise high
      the banner of the <i>True Dharma</i> [1], and to voice the sincere and truthful words of the
      venerable founder.</p>
      <footnotes>
        <footnote number="1">In Vietnamese: <i>Chánh Pháp</i> which can be translated as "True or Right Dharma" and refers to the true teachings of the Buddha.</footnote>
      </footnotes>
  </page>
  <page page="5">
    <p>In its efforts to survive and fulfill its mission, it has encountered numerous obstacles, yet
      also gained invaluable experiences, discerning who are friends and who are not, who truly are
      fellow practitioners and who are not sincere. More importantly, it is heartening to see that
      support for its cause is growing daily, with an increasing number of readers.</p>
    <p>These results bolster enthusiasm and determination, so stepping into the third year, Buddhism
      in Vietnam Journal vows to strive to achieve the outlined objectives, improving both content
      and form to align with the historical phase of Vietnamese Buddhism, catering to the foundation
      and aspirations of the readers. In terms of Buddhist doctrines, the journal will research and
      promote teachings that can address the anxieties and aspirations of people in the latter half
      of the twentieth century, Buddhist thoughts that can contribute to building a spiritual
      lifestyle for Vietnamese people, who are currently being swayed by foreign ideologies.</p>
    <p>In the field of arts and literature, will expand its scope,
      dedicating more pages to welcome new writers and nurture budding talents sympathetic to
      Buddhism. Additionally, the journal will have a section on Buddhist families, a growing
      organization for educating young Buddhists, yet lacking materials and theoretical foundations,
      essential for any movement. In this section, "Journal of Buddhism in Vietnam" welcomes all
      literary and artistic creations from all members of Buddhist families.</p>
    <p>Lastly—with a crucial point to make and to draw the reader's attention to this matter—it is
      the offspring of the General Association. </p>
    <footer>
      <b>BUDDHISM IN VIETNAM</b>
    </footer>
  </page>
  <page page="6">
    <p>With the mission to uphold the spirit of unified Buddhism, this journal vows to be a pioneer
      in the front lines of Buddhist unity and solidarity, breaking down all divisive thoughts and
      actions, welcoming goodwill and cooperative efforts in Buddhist unity. Starting from the next
      issue, we will discuss this topic extensively, exposing all aspects, seeking the root causes
      of the stagnation of Buddhist unity, proposing remedial measures, and laying out a specific,
      practical program to organize a congress of delegates from six Buddhist groups, akin to the
      1951 national Buddhist conference held at Từ Đàm.</p>
    <p>To prepare for such a Congress, "Journal of Buddhism in Vietnam" welcomes all opinions from
      readers, especially from those with authority in Buddhist groups. "Buddhism in Vietnam" will
      be delighted to serve as a free platform for all constructive opinions towards a real unity of
      Vietnamese Buddhism.</p>
  </page>
  <page page="7">
    <title>THE INDOMITABLE POWER OF THE SUBCONSCIOUS</title>
    <author>by Jadigh Kasyapa, translated by Tuệ Uyên</author>
    <p>We are always aware of one thing while forgetting another. As we walk down a path, we
      encounter a person and recognize them. After traveling some distance, we forget them, and
      their image fades from our consciousness. Another object, say a car or a house, draws our
      attention, and we see, know, and become aware of the car or house. After moving further, we
      again forget, and the image of the car or house is erased, making way for new images.</p>
    <p>Thus, as we become conscious of one thing, we forget another, continuing endlessly. From the
      moment of birth, this stream of perception and forgetting flows uninterrupted like a
      never-ending current. Even when we are not receiving external impressions, such as during
      sleep, this stream continues. At that time, old impressions resurface and are continuously
      obliterated in consciousness.</p>
    <p>However, we do not forget all things equally. Things that capture our attention significantly
      and make a strong impression linger longer in our minds, as the reverberation remains in the
      mind for a longer duration.</p>
  </page>
  <page page="8">
    <p>Conversely, something that barely captures our attention may be forgotten almost instantly
      upon perception. For instance, if we encounter an elephant on the street, the image of the
      elephant will persist for a long time in our mind, and even as we walk, we continue to
      remember the recently seen elephant. After a long distance, the image might still not be
      erased. If we meet an ordinary person without anything distinct, a few steps past them, we may
      forget them.</p>
    <p>However, what we forget is not entirely lost or obliterated. Whether we forget soon or later,
      whatever we know remains in our mind. We forget, but the image is not lost. Forgetting merely
      means storing it in the mind. Our mind is a vast container where all the ideas and images we
      have had or accepted are carefully stored. Everything we have thought, felt, or done remains
      there.</p>
    <p>We can recall these ideas and images in consciousness if we desire. Therefore, our mind
      consists of two parts: 1/ Perceptive, feeling, present activity. 2/ Storage of all thoughts
      and feelings we have forgotten.</p>
    <p>Psychologists refer to the first as consciousness and the second as the subconscious.</p>
  </page>
  <page page="9">
    <p>People often believe that what we remember is existing and active in consciousness, while
      what we forget has fallen into the subconscious, lying dormant or being obliterated there.
      This is a misconception. In reality, the contents of the subconscious are also active and
      strive to return to consciousness. As soon as they encounter conducive conditions, they can
      emerge in consciousness. Bergson stated, "Everything that we feel, seek, desire from our
      childhood still persists." These are trying to return to the present, merging with it to
      breach the fortress of consciousness, which always seeks to prevent their emergence.</p>
    <p>The Buddha taught similarly: A person's current personality is the result of all actions,
      feelings, and thoughts from time immemorial. The character of a thief is not like that of a
      saint because in the past, both characters acted and thought differently. What exists in the
      past is not destroyed; it persists in the present. Our past actions and thoughts always follow
      us like the path follows the footsteps of a yoke of oxen, or shadow follows a shape.</p>
    <p>Thus, the person we are today is crafted by our past, a faithful reflection of past actions
      and thoughts stored in our mind. What nature those past actions and thoughts hold, that is the
      nature of the present person. This precisely is the life and individuality of one. We create
      ourselves.</p>
  </page>
  <page page="10">
    <p>Outside of our mind (comprising consciousness and the subconscious), there are no other
      factors such as Spirit or Soul. We are truly our mind. A pure person is because their mind is
      full of pure thoughts and images. If the mind is filled with vile thoughts, then the person
      will be an impure one.</p>
    <p>However, some may doubt: If all our experiences, even the tiniest ones, are stored in the
      subconscious, why can we only remember a small portion of them?</p>
    <p>Thanks to the strength or weakness of consciousness, we can remember more or less. A strong
      consciousness can easily evoke images from the subconscious. Someone who practices meditation
      can calm their consciousness, and thus, consciousness becomes very powerful, enabling rapid
      recall of images. The normal person's consciousness constantly fluctuates, thus weaker in
      strength.</p>
    <p>The more concentrated and calm the consciousness, the stronger it becomes concerning the
      subconscious. The Buddha utilized the full strength of consciousness, remembering things from
      countless past lifetimes. There is nothing strange about it. All things are stored in the
      subconscious, and thanks to a concentrated strong consciousness, everything can be recalled.</p>
    <p>Not only when we are born do we have a subconscious. The subconscious has existed from time
      immemorial, each day becoming more enriched. Each image, sound, or thought enters the
      subconscious and is maintained eternally, never lost.</p>
    <title>WHAT IS THE PATH OF TRUTH?</title>
    <p>The Path of Truth is the <i>Eightfold Path</i> [1]. (It is the path of righteousness)<footnote
        number="1">[1]</footnote></p>
    <li>Right View (correct understanding, correct thought).</li>
    <li>Right Intent (correct resolve).</li>
    <li>Right Speech (correct speech).</li>
    <li>Right Action (correct conduct).</li>
    <li>Right Livelihood (correct livelihood).</li>
    <li>Right Effort (correct effort).</li>
    <li>Right Mindfulness (correct mindfulness).</li>
    <li>Right Concentration.</li>
    <g>The eight tenets constitute the path of the noble beings.</g>
    <footnotes>
      <footnote number="1">The <i>Eightfold Path</i> is a fundamental teaching in Buddhism that
        guides ethical and mental development towards enlightenment.</footnote>
    </footnotes>
  </page>
  <page page="11">
    <title>MASTER HUYỀN-TRANG'S JOURNEY TO INDIA TO SEEK THE BUDDHIST SUTRAS</title>
    <subtitle>Original Chinese Text by DƯƠNG ĐÌNH PHÚC</subtitle>
    <i>(Continued from previous issue)</i>
    <translator>NÔNG SƠN translated</translator>
    <p>On that day, Master Huyền-Trang set off with Shih Pan-Đà, arriving at Qua-Lô River at the
      third watch of the night, seeing the Ngọc-Môn Pass from afar. The river at this point was
      about ten <i>li</i> [2]<footnote number="1">[1]</footnote> upstream from the pass, and both
      banks were only about one <i>trượng</i> [3]<footnote number="2">[2]</footnote> apart, lined
      with straight <i>ngô đồng</i> trees. Together, master and disciple cut down a tree to make a
      bridge, spread grass, and packed sand on it to cross the river safely. Joyful, they sat down
      to rest on the grass.</p>
    <p>As dawn approached, Shih Pan-Đà suddenly drew a knife, hesitating in front of Master
      Huyền-Trang. Knowing his student's wavering intent, Master showed no fear, sat upright without
      rising, and stared steadfastly at him. Shih Pan-Đà laid down the knife, saying, "Disciple
      ponders as this journey lacks water, only near the five beacon towers are there grass and
      water. If our whereabouts were revealed at any point, our lives would end; it is better to
      return." Master Huyền-Trang firmly decided not to respond, allowing his disciple to return
      alone to Qua Châu, but Shih Pan-Đà hesitated, continuing, "If you are captured, and truthfully
      reveal my name, what would become of my wife, children, old, and young ones at home? Master
      Huyền-Trang swore by the heavens: "Rest assured, if by misfortune I am captured and
      dismembered, I will never reveal your name." Shih Pan-Đà, mounted his horse and returned
      eastward.</p>
    <footnotes>
      <footnote number="1"><i>Li</i> (里, Vietnamese: lý) is a traditional Chinese unit of distance,
        approximately equal to 0.5 kilometers.</footnote>
      <footnote number="2"><i>Trượng</i> (丈) is a traditional Chinese unit of length, equal to about
        3.3 meters.</footnote>
    </footnotes>
  </page>
  <page page="12">
    <p>From then on, Master Huyền-Trang traveled alone through the desert, vast expanses of sand
      with no endpoint in sight, moving forward based on piles of bones and the droppings of horses
      and camels. As shadows from distant objects cast upon the sand created fleeting and countless
      shapes, intimidating in their sudden illusions, Master, despite his arduous and perilous
      journey, held firm determination in his heart, thinking, "I fear not death, what then should I
      fear?" After traveling approximately eighty miles, a beacon tower appeared in the distance.
      Concerned about being spotted by the guards, he hid in a crevice and resumed his journey with
      nightfall.</p>
    <p>As the day declined, Master meticulously approached the beacon tower, spotting a pool of
      clear water. As he dismounted to fill his goatskin pouch with water, an arrow whistled over
      his head, followed closely by another nearly striking his knee. Realizing that the guards had
      discovered him, he had no choice but to shout, "Please do not shoot me! I am a monk from
      Tràng-An." Hearing this, the guards opened the gate and led him to meet the Prefect Vương
      Tường. Fortunately, Vương Tường was a Buddhist devotee who, after investigating, reverently
      respected Master, foreseeing the challenges of his western journey. He offered for Master to
      stay at Đôn Hoàng for support. Master firmly responded, "I am committed to seeking the
      Buddhist sutras, unconcerned for my life, enduring any hardship. If the Prefect insists on
      hindering my journey, I willingly accept all punishments, without taking a step back
      eastward." Deeply moved, Vương Tường hosted Master for a night. The next day, he gifted Master
      provisions and personally escorted him for ten miles, advising, "Follow this path to reach the
      fourth beacon tower. Prefect Vương Bá-Lung, a relative of mine with a kind heart, resides
      there. Tell him I sent you; he will surely assist." Parting ways with tearful eyes, Vương
      Tường bid farewell.</p>
    <p>In the evening, Master reached the fourth beacon tower, wary of obstruction from the guards,
      planning to stealthily obtain water and escape. While drawing water, he was startled by an
      arrow flying past, prompting him to shout as before, leading the guards to bring him before
      Vương Bá-Lung. Upon explaining his journey, Vương Bá-Lung provided him with a large leather
      pouch of water and provisions for the horse, advising him to avoid the fifth station due to
      the Prefect's harshness, recommending a route that bypassed it, proceeding straight to the
      Wild Horse Springs. From there, traveling westward to Mạc-Hạ Duyên-Tích, an area of rocky
      riverbeds, stretching eight hundred miles named Sa-Hà (also called Lưu-Sa, or the modern-day
      Qua-Bích desert), devoid of water and vegetation. Vương Bá-Lung urged Master to tread
      cautiously a thousand times over.</p>
    <p>Thus, taking leave of Vương-Bá-Lung, Master set forth towards Wild Horse Springs and Mạc-Hạ
      Duyên-Tích. In this arid expanse, devoid of any signs of life, human or animal, Master and his
      lone shadow pressed on for a full day under the shrouding sandstorm, losing his way, unable to
      locate Wild Horse Springs. Weary to the core, he dismounted to drink from his water pouch,
      accidentally spilling its contents onto the desert floor—an irreplaceable loss in such
      desolation. Disheartened, considering going back to the fourth beacon tower for water, he
      retraced his steps eastward over ten miles. Yet remembering his vow not to retreat east until
      reaching India, he resolved, "Better to perish westward than survive by regressing eastward!"
      Redirecting his horse westward, he pressed forward confidently.</p>
    <p>Surrounded by blurring landscapes, amidst night and raging desert windstorms resembling
      torrential summer rain, Master continued steadfastly for four nights and five days without a
      drop of water, initially sensing dryness in his tongue, eventually feeling parched throughout,
      breathing becoming labored with both lungs parched, struggling to open his eyes. His horse
      also stood motionless, both lying near a stone. On the fifth night, a sudden cool wind like
      dousing oneself in refreshing cold water rejuvenated him. His spirit revived slowly, able to
      open his eyes and his horse regained strength to move.</p>
    <p>The horse struggled to travel a few miles, discovering a vibrant patch of green where a
      crystal-clear spring emerged. Elated, Master dismounted, drinking fully and allowing his horse
      to drink until satisfied, resting on the grass for a day and resuming his journey, eventually
      crossing Mạc-Hạ Duyên-Tích and reaching the borders of Y-Ngô.</p>
  </page>
  <page page="13">
    <p>Upon entering Y-Ngô, Master lodged at the Y-Ngô Monastery. There, an elderly Chinese monk,
      hearing of Master's arrival, hastily came out without fully dressing, barefooted, embracing
      Master with tearful joy, exclaiming, "Who knew I would meet a countryman in this remote
      place."</p>
    <p>Master stayed in Y-Ngô for over ten days, receiving the king's offerings. At that time, the
      neighboring country of Cao Xương, hearing of a distinguished Chinese monk passing through
      Y-Ngô, promptly dispatched an envoy requesting Y-Ngô's king to send Master to Cao Xương.
      Master originally intended to travel directly from Y-Ngô through the northern forests of Mount
      Tian Shan to India but now obliged to detour to Cao Xương. Accompanied by the Cao-Xương envoy,
      he traveled southwest for six days through rocky terrain, arriving at Cao Xương's border in
      the afternoon of the sixth day. The king, Khúc Văn Thái, personally received Master outside
      the palace, with utmost reverence, saying, "For a master to cross the desert alone is most
      astonishing. Upon hearing of your name, I have eagerly awaited, unable to eat or sleep,
      calculating that you might arrive today. Thus, my entire family refrained from sleep, awaiting
      your sermons." Soon, concubines and high officials arrived to pay respects. Khúc-Văn-Thái and
      Master conversed until midnight before the king retired. The next day, Master remained on his
      bed, unable to rise.</p>
    <footer>Master Huyền Trang - Journey Through Hardships</footer>
  </page>
  <page page="14">
    <p>Khúc Văn Thái visited Master and expressed, "I greatly admire you, yearning to serve you for
      life. I earnestly request that you remain with us, allowing our people to benefit from your
      teachings." Master thanked Khúc Văn Thái for his profound hospitality, yet reiterated his
      determination to reach India. Despite Khúc Văn Thái's repeated, sincere requests, Master
      resolutely refused, and ultimately, Khúc Văn Thái thought to deepen their bond by attending to
      Master meticulously, ensuring his comfort, from meals to clothing and supplies. At each meal,
      Khúc Văn Thái personally presented the tray, standing respectfully by Master's side.</p>
    <p>Despite appreciating Khúc Văn Thái's sincerity, Master perceived he might never reach India
      and firmly declared, "I traverse distant lands, dedicated to seeking the Buddhist sutras,
      impeded solely by the king's custody. The king may retain my corpse, but not my spirit and
      resolve." Thereupon, Master sat unmoving and speaking nothing, fasting for three entire days
      until his breath weakened, and his body became frail. Deeply moved, Khúc Văn Thái relented,
      bowing in farewell, requesting only that Master teach the <i>Nhân-Vương Bát Nhã</i> [4] sutra
      for a month and agree to become non-blood siblings, allowing him to proceed. Master accepted
      and resumed eating as before.</p>
    <p>After a month, Master prepared to depart. Before leaving, Khúc Văn Thái equipped Master with
      supplies for a twenty-year journey, presenting one hundred ounces of gold, thirty thousand
      silver coins, five hundred silk garments, thirty horses, four monks, and twenty-five
      attendants. He also composed twenty-four letters for the rulers of twenty-four countries
      Master would traverse, seeking their assistance. Grateful, Master wrote a eulogy "Thanks to
      the King of Cao Xương," expressing gratitude to Khúc Văn Thái. On the day of departure, the
      king, royal court, monks, and nearly the entire populace escorted Master westward out of the
      capital. Khúc Văn Thái clasped his hand unwilling to part, weeping, and none could hold back
      their tears, watching until Master disappeared from view, reluctantly returning home.</p>
    <footnotes>
      <footnote number="4"><i>Nhân-Vương Bát Nhã</i> refers to the "Perfection of Wisdom" literature
        meant for rulers in Buddhist teachings.</footnote>
    </footnotes>
  </page>
  <page page="15">
    <p>From Cao Xương, Master Huyền-Trang proceeded westward through A-Kỳ-Ni (Yanqi County, Xinjiang
      Uyghur Autonomous Region), circling Yin Mountain (now the Gaokutsatimayudong or Dry Mountain
      Pass) to Kucha (also known as Qiuci, present-day Kuqa County, Xinjiang). Delayed by heavy
      snowfall that blanketed the mountain passes, he stayed in Qiuci for sixty days. Here, he met
      Muktokuta, a scholar who had spent twenty years in India studying Buddhist scriptures and
      commanded great respect. Master frequently engaged with him in deep Buddhist discourse,
      leading Muktokuta to remark, "This Chinese monk's profound knowledge is unmatched; even in
      India, finding a scholar of his caliber would be a challenge."</p>
    <p>Departing from Qiuci, Master traveled west for sixty miles, crossing a small desert to Baluka
      (also known as Kumkapha, modern-day Bai Cheng and Atush, Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region),
      spending a night there before continuing west thirty miles to Lemedhian Mountains
      (Baghrashıshan, part of the Tian Shan range). The path was entirely mountainous, the mountains
      perennially capped in snow, appearing a stark white against the icy sky, with severe cold and
      constant sifting snow throughout the day. Certain stretches were rough, with treacherous
      boulders, others were sheer cliffs towering thousands of feet which Master traversed
      cautiously, clinging to the precarious rocky ledges.</p>
    <p>In the mountains, there was not a single dry spot; by day, cooking was accomplished with pots
      suspended mid-air, at night, sleep was on icy platforms. Traversing seven days and nights
      finally cleared the high mountains, where escorts from Cao Xương, fearing hardship, fled, some
      succumbing to the cold in the mountains. Many mules and horses perished, leaving only a
      handful accompanying Master.</p>
    <p>Emerging from Lemethian, he followed the Karachin River, crossing the Kuna Lun Mountains to a
      vast lake called Hot Sea (Lake Alakol, Kazakhstan). Looking endless and unbounded, its waters
      spiraled rapidly like unleashed arrows; despite calm, its waves towered several feet. Master
      advanced along the lake's northwestern shore for five hundred miles, reaching Taltak Marak
      (Tartous, Kyrgyzstan). There, he encountered Great Kushan King Yehuda hunting, a relative of
      Khúc Văn Thái. Master offered the letter of introduction from Khúc Văn Thái, and King Yehuda
      was delighted, ordering escorts for Master.</p>
    <p>Passing Noshirwan (Talgarat), Altai (-Khizbin Talwakka: region of Afghanistan) and Lake
      Khotan (-Madang: region of Afghanistan), revered Turpan Pass was a hazard; sheer cliffs soared
      on both sides, the slope narrow and vertiginous. Descending could mean certain death with
      prevalent ash rock. Emerging from the pass into the late Thsara Khan (-region of Afghanistan),
      amidst an expansive desert, just before reaching Piscataquy (-region of Afghanistan), Yehuda's
      escort returned, leaving Master alone upon arrival at Pihar's residence (-region of
      Afghanistan), surrendering engulfed by Spitak River, traveling a thousand-six hundred miles.</p>
    <footer>Master Huyền Trang - Trials and Triumphs</footer>
  </page>
  <page page="16">
    <p>Master Huyền Trang ventured through northern India, journeying along the Ganges River
      eastward. First, he arrived at Dyankugan (Agra, India), bordered north by Nepal and south by
      the Na Bada River. Its capital, Guenê (now Bulandshahr) on the Ganges's west bank, hosted
      hundreds of monasteries with thousands of monks. Master resided for three months at the
      Brahmaputra, Kalaw, and Guna monasteries, further traveling northeast, reverently visiting six
      great sacred Buddhist sites.</p>
    <p>Moving from Guenê to Salupâ (also called Shāvatthi, Sön Bhavi and Pavvietal within Sa Lait
      province), the longstanding domicile of Sakyamuni Buddha, the origins of Buddhism, and
      followed Vamnika (-Pavvietal forest flourishing Rantalawat), hoping to advance his stirring
      teachings by enduring rustic regions, furthering contemplation indispensable concentration.</p>
    <p>From Salupâ, following Lanka (-Naur Hill, profound fundamental Mandalay of the mythical
      kiln), Pataliputra (Nalbari, south of Vintaoya Province), birthed ideas requisite instituted
      perennial (paving event Baiyi) thought processes of the eons to exist incapable without
      enacting Swearing Reading Judgment Tsumati transcendence, embodied profound enlightenment
      paving the path.</p>
    <footer>End of the Trail</footer>
  </page>
  <page number="19">
    <section>
      <title>Venerable Xuanzang's Journey</title>
      <p> In Lặc-Tư, India, there is a temple named Lộc-Dã. It is where after attaining
        enlightenment, the Buddha first delivered a sermon to Kiều-Trần-Như. He worshipped at Lộc-Dã
        temple, then crossed the Ganges to the land of Ma-Yết-Đa (modern-day Bihar, Northeast
        India), with the capital Vương Xá-Thành (Rajagrha, located in Magadha). There are 50 temples
        in the city, housing 10,000 monks, where the Buddha delivered sermons and where, after his
        passing, the first committee of 500 A-la-hán conducted the first compilation of the <i>Tam
        Tạng</i><footnote number="1">[1]</footnote>. He stayed for 7 days before heading west for 6
        days to arrive at the Bồ-Đề Già garden in Đạt-Đề-La-Già monastery (now Bodh Gaya, Bihar,
        Northeast India). After 6 years of ascetic practice following his renunciation, the Buddha
        attained enlightenment at the Bodhi tree there, worshipping for 6 days before studying at
        Na-Lan-Đà monastery. </p>
      <p> Na-Lan-Đà monastery in Ma-Yết-Đa, Central India, known as the Heavenly Unending Monastery,
        was established in the first century and is the grandest and most magnificent monastery in
        India, serving as a cultural center at that time. All scriptures of the Mahayana and
        Theravada, chants of the <i>Veda</i><footnote number="2">[2]</footnote>, as well as books on
        medicine, astronomy, geography, and technology converge there; its head was Giới Hiền
        Pháp-sư, called Chánh-Pháp-Tạng, over 100 years old, and the leading scholar in India at the
        time. </p>
      <p>
        The monks at Na-Lan-Đà were informed of Venerable Huyền Trang's arrival and dispatched 200
        monks and 1,000 people to welcome him. Amid applause and admiration from the crowd,
        Venerable Huyền Trang entered Na-Lan-Đà, the highest seat of learning in India at the time.
      </p>
      <p> Upon arrival, Venerable Huyền Trang, along with others, performed rituals and acknowledged
        Giới Hiền as his teacher. Although Giới Hiền had stopped teaching due to old age, he made an
        exception to lecture on the <i>Yogacara</i><footnote number="3">[3]</footnote> texts for
        Venerable Huyền Trang, which took 15 months to complete. Each lecture attracted around 3,000
        to 4,000 attendees. The monastery housed 10,000 monks, and among them, 1,000 could explain
        20 scriptures, 500 could explain 30, and 10, including Venerable Huyền Trang, could expound
        50 scriptures; while only Giới Hiền could fully comprehend all scriptures. </p>
      <p>
        Venerable Huyền Trang, dedicated every day and evening to his studies for five years,
        seeking to thoroughly understand the profound meanings of the scriptures. His renowned
        scholarship spread across India, yet he remained unsatisfied and thus bade farewell to Giới
        Hiền to continue his studies in Southern India.
      </p>
      <footer>
        (To be continued)
      </footer>
    </section>
    <footnotes>
      <footnote number="1">Tam Tạng (三藏): Tripitaka, the traditional term for Buddhist scriptures.</footnote>
      <footnote number="2">Veda (वेद): Sacred scriptures of Hinduism, known also as Phệ Đà in
        Vietnamese.</footnote>
      <footnote number="3">Yogacara (瑜伽行派): The "Yoga Practice School," a doctrinal system from the
        Mahayana Buddhist tradition.</footnote>
    </footnotes>
  </page>

  <page number="20">
    <section>
      <title>Queries</title>
      <i>For Young Buddhists</i>
      <p>
        When human beings become too greedy, they are always troubled with worries. They desire a
        beautiful dress to last eternally, and wish a beloved friend to remain unchanged forever.
      </p>
      <p>
        Thus, a heart deeply in love is constantly anxious and worried. In this anxiety, people seek
        to protect and preserve that which they love. Without love, without passionate care, there
        is no life, and it is believed that anxiety is essential for one who knows how to live.
      </p>
      <p>
        While enchanting, that notion is filled with romantic qualities, sufficing only for the
        idealism of the olden leisure class. Desiring a beautiful dress to last forever or wishing a
        friend never to depart—if examined through Buddhism, these desires are a form of greed,
        naive and innocent. Recognizing the impermanence of all things, wishing something temporary
        could remain unchanged, how can it not be considered foolish?
      </p>
      <p>
        Wishing earnestly for a beloved not to depart is the same. This longing for eternity, this
        insatiable craving convinces me when I look into the eyes of one I love and say: "You will
        not die; I do not want you to die." However, recognizing the truth of impermanence, knowing
        that one day death will take my dear friend from me, I can no longer claim that they will
        not die.
      </p>
      <p>
        A deep sorrow tears at the heart; I grasp the hand of my beloved and say, despairingly: "You
        must not die, although you will die." How painful it is!
      </p>
      <p>
        Anxiety, worry? That is the attitude of the unwise. The dew drop on the tip of the grass
        reminds us not to crave permanence in things that cannot be perpetual. Is this a path to
        negativity? No. Listen to the poetry of a Vietnamese master from the Lý dynasty:
      </p>
      <p> Vạn Hạnh Thiền sư wrote: <br /><i>"Thân như điện ảnh hữu hoàn vô, Vạn mộc xuân vinh thu
          hựu khô. Nhậm vận thịnh suy vô bố úy, Thịnh suy như lộ thảo đầu phô."</i>
      </p>
      <p> Master Mật-Thể translated: <br /><i>"This fleeting body as lightening's illusion, <br />Spring's
        verdure succumbs to autumn's desolation. <br />Let rise and fall take their course without
        fear, <br />Like morning dew on the tip of the blade."</i>
      </p>
      <p>
        How liberating the words of a sage! A worldly person views prosperity and decay with eyes
        filled with anxiety and fear. But under the tranquil and composed demeanor of the
        enlightened, prosperity and decline bear no significance, and cannot shake a resolute mind
        that has distanced from the six desires and seven emotions.
      </p>
    </section>
    <footnotes>
      <footnote number="1">Teenagers of yore refer to young people from older societal classes
        preoccupied with romanticized ideals.</footnote>
    </footnotes>
  </page>

  <page number="21">
    <section>
      <title>The Fleeting Nature of Life</title>
      <p>
        <i>Spring passes, all flowers fall, Spring arrives, all flowers bloom. Matters before us
          come and go, Age over the head slowly grows. Do not tell me all flowers withered as spring
          ends, Last night a single plum blossom bloomed in the front courtyard.</i>
      </p>
      <p>
        All things follow the law of impermanence, combining and separating. Though they perish,
        they do not cease to exist entirely. The eternal essence of all things transcends endless
        time and boundless space. When spring arrives, cherry blossoms reveal their beauty. As
        spring transitions to summer, autumn is heralded by lotus wilting and chrysanthemums
        blooming. Who could have imagined that in the midst of storm and wind last night, in the
        cold of winter, a plum branch would bloom. Nature is always in blossom, and only our hearts
        fail to synchronize with the vibrant rhythm of life.
      </p>
      <p>
        What have these verses conveyed to us?
      </p>
      <p>
        I hold an ideal.
        Yet I worry and fret over it. Because I do not perceive my ideal through the Buddha's
        teachings, I have sought to protect it with all the greed in my heart. I have not heeded the
        wisdom of the forebears and naïvely longed for the everlasting permanence of what cannot
        eternally endure. I am no longer naïve. I must become wiser.
      </p>
      <p>
        I understand that the rise and fall should not trouble me. A beautiful form or great
        quantity doesn't signify prosperity. Immense latent power doesn't imply decline. To focus on
        outcomes, worrying over gain and loss, is a futile endeavour. Here, I recognize the core
        issue of the ideal: to invest all thoughts and energy in construction and creation, without
        worrying about the result. If I do not succeed later, it may be due to the task exceeding my
        capacity.
      </p>
      <p> I can still assure myself: I have done my utmost. This is the greatest success in the
        ideal life of a young man. This most wise attitude, I've learnt from the <i>Bodhisattvas</i><footnote
          number="1">[2]</footnote>, without a hint of regret. </p>
      <p>
        Avoid the wicked, do not befriend the licentious, only serve with sages to hope for
        enlightenment.
      </p>
      <p>
        Manslaughter may seem forgivable; malicious schemes to harm, such intentions are not
        approvable.
      </p>
      <p>
        When calamity strikes, a true friend's heart is revealed, conflicts unveil strength and
        intelligence, debates identify wisdom, and scarce crops show true kindness.
      </p>
      <footer>
        (Hiền-Nhân Sutra)
      </footer>
    </section>
    <footnotes>
      <footnote number="1">Bodhisattva (菩薩): Enlightened beings who remain in the world to help
        others reach enlightenment.</footnote>
      <footnote number="2">Ideal life refers to the life aspirations one aims for, in line with
        Buddhist wisdom.</footnote>
    </footnotes>
  </page>

  <page number="22">
    <section>
      <title>A Short Story Awarded Consolation Prize</title>
      <author>by MINH TRÂM</author>
      <p>
        This is a poor neighborhood, where roads remain muddy throughout the year, heaps of garbage
        pile high, hosting swarms of flies and mosquitoes. During rainy days, mud reaches
        ankle-deep. Saigon, the "Pearl of the Orient," the flamboyant capital, has never cast its
        light on these dilapidated huts with straw roofs and battered walls.
      </p>
      <p>
        Yet, people still live here. There are emaciated children, clothes failing to cover their
        bellies, spending daily idle time near the towering piles of trash, while their mothers work
        as hired hands to support the family. The fathers typically work as laborers, cyclo drivers,
        or sometimes find themselves unemployed and lying sick in dark corners of their homes.
      </p>
      <p>
        Life flows slowly here. Everyone patiently waits for a brighter tomorrow, knowing well that
        it remains a distant dream. The monthly wages of a laborer barely meet living expenses, and
        once daily ride costs and taxes are accounted for, a cyclo driver's income only stretches to
        the next market day, a cause for contentment. Yet, what can be done? Hope must sustain life,
        just as the occasional sunbeam finds its way through the straw-leaved roof offering a moment
        of joy to the downtrodden.
      </p>
      <p>
        Thầy Ký's house is among these humble homes. It's also a thatched wall, straw-roofed house,
        yet slightly cleaner, with two or three windows painted blue, lending some color to the
        dreary surroundings. The fence is also tidier, with panels still bearing the ivory hue of
        fresh bamboo.
      </p>
      <p>
        When Thầy Ký first moved here, everyone was startled. The children gathered around,
        fascinated by the seemingly luxurious though old suitcases, marvelling at the ba gác vehicle
        carrying furniture. The varnished divan and the mirrored wardrobe, rare among the
        neighborhood, all seemed to display an air of affluence from their owner.
      </p>
      <p>
        And indeed, their owner didn't resemble dông Hà or Năm of sugarcane juice fame, with
        unassuming clothes but a face with intellectual features, bright eyes on a straight, high
        nose. "He's an educated man," the neighbors whispered, "maybe fallen on hard times," another
        added. From then, they called him Thầy Ký, though yet unaware of his occupation. His wife,
        young, and pale-skinned, was said to be "charming if she made up," as the locals assessed.
      </p>
      <p>
        Gradually, a few neighboring children came over to Thầy Ký's house to see their reflections
        in the mirror, and each time their mothers fetched them, a few words were exchanged with Cô
        Ký. She was sweet, without a hint of disdain. From then on, for matters involving literacy,
        people suggested seeking out Thầy Ký. Be it job applications, ID card replacement forms, or
        any document, Thầy Ký willingly assisted without charge. The couple had one child,
        6-year-old Tấn, whose round face and sharp eyes were noted. Tấn longed to play with friends
        of his age but didn't dare venture to the garbage heap fearing his mother's scolding.
      </p>
      <p>
        That morning, as Cô Ký was busy cooking, Tấn ran in requesting five đồng for ice cream.
      </p>
      <p>
        But Tấn's mother shook her head, "You'll eat soon; no more money for now."
      </p>
      <p>
        Pouting momentarily, Tấn quietly left. His mother followed with a sigh, her eyes shimmering
        with tears. Since her husband became unemployed and they had to sell their urban house to
        settle in this grubby neighborhood, she had numerous times sorrowfully watched Tấn wander
        somberly along the muddy trench in front of their home, beside a scrawny dog. Who would have
        thought their beautiful child would endure such hardship, with possibly worse to come.
      </p>
    </section>
    <footnotes>
      <footnote number="1">Thầy Ký refers to an affable educational figure who was revered for his
        knowledge and dignity.</footnote>
      <footnote number="2">Ba gác, a type of tricycle used in Vietnam for transporting goods.</footnote>
    </footnotes>
  </page>

  <page number="23">
    <section>
      <title>The Turning Point</title>
      <p>
        Hearing the sound of footsteps outside, she eagerly looked out. He had returned, his face
        darkened by sun exposure lighting up in joy. She was anxiously hopeful. As he took off his
        shoes, he began:
      </p>
      <p>
        "Went searching places where they promised work, but everyone was out. Frustrated, I headed
        home, luckily running into ông Nguyên, who pointed me to a warehouse job offering two
        thousand monthly. I rushed, got accepted immediately, and start tomorrow."
      </p>
      <p>
        Her face brightened immediately. She bustled about setting the table. Tấn rushed inside,
        tattling that mother refused money for ice cream.
      </p>
      <p>
        "None left," she explained to her husband. He smiled and told their son, "I'll get you
        plenty of treats once I start work tomorrow; we're out of money now." As he spoke, he handed
        over the last đồng to Tấn, saying:
      </p>
      <p>
        "Give it to mother to save for later.”
      </p>
      <p>
        Tấn giggled heartily, clinging to his father's neck, while Cô Ký turned away to hide her
        tears.
      </p>
      <p>
        Since then, the family grew happier. His main focus was working twice daily, and no amount
        of fatigue, even being reprimanded by the boss or enduring the long journey, could survive
        Tấn's joyous greeting—they would evade his mind. Their cramped home seemed to glow with the
        innocent laugh of a child, for his sake, he endured all hardships.
      </p>
      <p>
        Cô Ký too was elated. She began planning to save enough to renovate their house for
        cleanliness, replacing the straw roof with tin, joining a savings group for buying a sewing
        machine, and sewing for a living to save for Tấn's schooling.
      </p>
      <p>
        Beautiful dreams blossomed under their modest but harmonious roof. Yet, life's
        unpredictability shattered their hopeful bubbles the very morning this occurred.
      </p>
      <p>
        While tidying up the house, she saw her husband arriving sluggishly, his face somber.
        Recognizing foreboding news, she set aside the broom and hurried to meet him.
      </p>
      <p>
        Once inside, he sighed deeply, collapsing into his seat, and said: "Lost my job again!"
      </p>
      <p>
        He continued without waiting for her to ask:
      </p>
      <p>
        "They coaxed me into stealing goods from the warehouse for money to share. I couldn't
        comply, and they found an excuse to fire me before I leaked their plan."
      </p>
      <p>
        The entire world seemed to collapse before her. She forced herself to ask her husband:
      </p>
      <p>
        "Who persuaded? What did they accuse you of taking?"
      </p>
      <p>
        "The warehouse manager himself; what else? Came boldly proposing during breakfast. I felt
        suspicious seeing him, usually so pompous, suddenly inviting me to eat phở. As expected,
        over breakfast, he hatched a theft plan. Rejecting immediately, I stood and left. That noon,
        he called me in, said: 'Think over. Refuse, and you'll lose your job.' I remained firm, and
        he handed back my wages.”
      </p>
      <p>
        Opening his wallet, he gave her the half-month's salary and said:
      </p>
      <p>
        "That's all for now, handle wisely while I look for something else."
      </p>
      <p>
        Silently listening, she finally told him:
      </p>
      <p>
        "They make you such an offer, try explaining gently; abruptly dismissing leaves them
        humiliated, no wonder they retaliated."
      </p>
      <p>
        "Why such torment for us?" she lamented, a deep sorrow in her voice making it hard for her
        upset husband to scold her. Patiently, he replied:
      </p>
      <p> "Dear, all this time we have lived peacefully together. Why invite worry unnecessarily?
        Don't lament anymore. Just look; what meaning does this life hold? Here today, gone
        tomorrow. Once well-off, now like this. Is it not crucial to be self-aware, to live with a
        peaceful heart, free from attachment to the <i>Tham</i><footnote number="1">[1]</footnote>? </p>
      <p>
        "But what comfort is there in hardship? Maintaining purity loses jobs, leaves children
        hungry."
      </p>
      <p>
        Mentioning their child, he glanced at the boy playing outside. Unconsciously, he sighed
        deeply. His wife was right in some respects; their child did nothing wrong to suffer. For a
        moment, he regretted refusing the manager's proposal. In this deceitful society, the
        truthful inevitably struggle. Knowing this, why didn't he just...
      </p>
    </section>
    <footnotes>
      <footnote number="1">Tham (貪): Greed or excessive desire, particularly as one of the three
        poisons in Buddhist teachings.</footnote>
    </footnotes>
  </page>

  <page number="24">
    <section>
      <p> But immediately, he reproached himself. Would fleeting wealth have lasted, brought true
        happiness, or was it merely an illusion entangling him in <i>Tham, Sân, Si</i><footnote
          number="1">[1]</footnote>? This delusion invites suffering swiftly. Evil deeds carry
        consequences, if not this life, then the next; thus endless cycles of karma bound him. </p>
      <p>
        Speaking gently, he answered his wife:
      </p>
      <p>
        "Do you no longer believe in karma? Honest work barely sustains, let alone those evildoers.
        I deeply fear present karma, so for myself, for our child, I dare not follow them."
      </p>
      <p>
        "You're too righteous, being upright means watching the child starve tomorrow."
      </p>
      <p>
        Realizing her integrity suffered due to worry, he bore her temperament patiently. Seeking
        another job would demonstrate how virtue eventually meets fortune.
      </p>
      <p>
        Yet, fortune continued to elude him. Perhaps Buddha intended further testing; now over a
        month passed with no work found. Each place was either requiring wait or had enough people.
        Bitterness often tempted thoughts of drowning to escape the wife's weary face and the
        child's tearful eyes. But at the riverbank, reflection overcame him: death wasn't the end,
        only compounding karma for the next life; besides, his death wouldn't end their suffering.
      </p>
      <p>
        So he quietly returned home.
      </p>
      <p>
        That evening he arrived, finding the door shut. Little over seven, surprised, he entered.
        His wife, hearing him:
      </p>
      <p>
        "You're back? Any luck today?"
      </p>
      <p>
        "No," he replied simply. "Sleeping early?"
      </p>
      <p>
        Under faint light, he saw Tấn's face flushed. Alarmed, he asked:
      </p>
      <p>
        "Is he sick?"
      </p>
      <p>
        "Feverish since noon."
      </p>
      <p>
        "Given any medicine yet?"
      </p>
      <p>
        "A leftover pill from the cabinet earlier." She replied somberly.
      </p>
      <p>
        Quickly removing his coat, he rushed to feel his son's forehead. Heat radiated visibly.
        Anxiously, he instructed her to apply more oil and cover him warmly. The fevered child
        tossed restlessly, delirious. All night he remained at Tấn's side. The fever continued
        unchecked.
      </p>
      <p>
        Despite trying medicines—traditional, folk, even credit-bought herbal decoctions from the
        neighborhood doctor—Tấn remained unchanged days later. Suspecting typhoid, he knew
        hospitalization entailed immense cost, while their funds were nonexistent. Watching his
        wife, especially his child whom illness had emaciated, leaving sunken eyes with black rings,
        drove him to near madness.
      </p>
      <p>
        All he knew was that his child was nearing death, and money was vital to save him. A notion
        fleetingly crossed his mind: approach the manager, accepting all his terms if advanced
        sufficient funds for hospital care.
      </p>
      <p>
        Preparing to call his wife to tend their son, Tấn opened his eyes hearing sounds of
        movement. Weakly, he inquired where he was headed.
      </p>
      <p>
        "To get money for oranges. Want some?"
      </p>
      <p>
        Recalling Tấn persistently pleaded for oranges amid fever only days prior, leaving both
        parents tearfully helpless, he improvised endless excuses to comfort him. Hearing his
        desire, Tấn's dim eyes brightened:
      </p>
      <p>
        "Please get me some. The other day you said the Buddha had many oranges. Tell him, I stopped
        fighting with Tý and am being good; He'll give lots of oranges to me and you and mom too,
        right?"
      </p>
      <p>
        Tears welled unexpectedly. His comforting lie stayed long in the child's memory; now, what
        could be done?
      </p>
      <p>
        Flustered, he hesitated, but Tấn insisted impatiently.
      </p>
      <p>
        "Go now, please."
      </p>
      <p>
        Yet he procrastinated stepping forth. Outdone, destined to barter his moral integrity? Had
        life already defeated and crushed his inner pureness? How bitter, humiliating!
      </p>
      <p>
        "Not going for oranges, says he's no longer fond of me?"
      </p>
      <p>
        Thoughtlessly he assured her like a machine.
      </p>
      <p>
        "Going! Right away! Sleep a bit, then I'll bring them."
      </p>
      <p>
        Obediently, Tấn squeezed his eyes shut tight.
      </p>
    </section>
    <footnotes>
      <footnote number="1">Tham, Sân, Si (貪瞋癡): Greed, anger, and ignorance, the three poisons in
        Buddhism that cause suffering.</footnote>
    </footnotes>
  </page>

  <page number="25">
    <section>
      <p>
        He assured his son of going, though he possessed little hope. Up until now, the arrangement
        had floundered and they may no longer consider him worthy. Regardless, he resolved to try.
      </p>
      <p>
        His steps led him along familiar paths. Passing a temple, radiating light and fragrant
        incense, filled with devout laypeople earnestly chanting, he thought bitterly: "Buddha, Gods
        do not heed my woes despite repeated prayers. They are beyond reach!" In his despair, he
        lost all faith. Pressing onward.
      </p>
      <p>
        Suddenly, he collided with a passerby. Raising his head to apologize, he attempted moving on
        when a hand grasped his.
      </p>
      <p>
        "Hey there!"
      </p>
      <p>
        Realization dawned that it was a once-close friend, Giác. Yet Giác appeared affluent,
        wearing expensive clothes and twinkling golden-rimmed glasses. Instantly self-conscious over
        his worn attire.
      </p>
      <p>
        "Why so absent-minded? Where heading?"
      </p>
      <p>
        "Off to find rice," he forced a smile responding. "Where do you live now, for a visit soon,
        apologies, really in a hurry."
      </p>
      <p>
        "No, not after such a long time apart, you must. I reside nearby."
      </p>
      <p>
        Giác, extending an arm, pulled him towards an upscale house at the street's end. With great
        cheer, Giác inquired after his family, reminiscing older times. Eventually, Giác stated:
      </p>
      <p>
        "I've been seeking you, you know."
      </p>
      <p>
        "For what purpose?"
      </p>
      <p>
        "To oversee accounts at my stores. Previous hires couldn't manage. Trusted hands only, you
        understand? Stay, have dinner, and we'll discuss this further.”
      </p>
      <p>
        Yet he hesitated, wishing to share joyous news with his wife. Pressed without options, Giác
        added:
      </p>
      <p>
        "Why not escort me back—visit your wife, greet your child, treating the little one to some
        gifts.”
      </p>
      <p>
        Upon his and this remarkable friend's return, Tấn slept still. Carefully, they arranged the
        juicy, red oranges Giác gifted near him and then joyfully rejoined their guest.
      </p>
      <p>
        Giác departed when his wife rejoined from the kitchen. Proudly, he told her:
      </p>
      <p>
        "See, I mentioned today I’d bring good news! Working for Giác carries great promise. He
        might entrust us with managing an entire store!"
      </p>
      <p>
        "Even the Buddhas must guide us; we’re overwhelmed with relief," she joyously concurred.
      </p>
      <p>
        "Come now, only realizing Phật and Gods exist now, are we?" he teased her.
      </p>
      <p>
        Internally though, deep regret washed over him. But a step remained to spiral into
        wrongdoing. The fraudulent life nearly claimed him, squeezing out his conscience. Avoiding
        present adversity availed him future dilemmas, legal or otherwise. Yet, relieved, he
        shivered considering closer reality of wrongdoing. Both literally teetering at the
        precipice, miraculous intervention propelled him clear. Simultaneously, illumination
        unleashed within. Could this be נוRic insight illuminating his true path, beyond the trials
        Buddha put forth, enabling his friend’s aiding encounter?
      </p>
      <p>
        Seeing him persist in contemplation, his wife remarked:
      </p>
      <p>
        "Little one's probably delighted about the orange."
      </p>
      <p>
        Tấn awoke just then. Oranges lay scattered closeby. Baffled, he rubbed his eyes, then
        glanced from mother to father, at the radiant fruits surrounding him. Embracing them
        protectively as if fearing they'd vanish, jubilant he asked:
      </p>
      <p>
        "Buddha's gifts, father?"
      </p>
      <p>
        "Indeed Buddha's gifts, stay good—He'll grant many more things, someday I'll bring them
        home. But you must thank Him first."
      </p>
      <p>
        Tears shimmered as his son reverently clasped hands, eyes closed earnestly proclaiming:
      </p>
      <p>
        "Thank you, Buddha!"
      </p>
      <footer>
        Note: To aid Buddhist scholars in their studies, Thiều-Chửu's Sino-Vietnamese Dictionary has
        been reprinted, featuring many Buddhist terms. Available at Hưng-Long Printing House, 117
        Tôn Thất-Đạm (formerly Chaigneau, near Nam-Việt cinema). Price: 260. Discount applied.
      </footer>
    </section>
  </page>
  <page number="26">
    <section>
      <title>Documents</title>
      <subsection>
        <title>Buddhist Family Group</title>
        <author>NGUYỄN-KHẮC-TỪ</author>
        <p> As previously stated in "Vietnamese Buddhism Turns Two," from this issue onwards, we
          dedicate several pages to discussing the Buddhist Family Group. We begin with excerpts
          from the "Buddhist Family Group Documents," meticulously compiled by a Central Region
          leader, Nguyễn-Khắc-Từ. This foundational material is essential for anyone planning to
          establish a Buddhist Family Group or a leader wishing to contribute. Though specific to
          the Central Region, the principles can be applied across Vietnamese Buddhist Family
          Groups. We hope for a National Leader's Conference soon to resolve minor discrepancies.
          Nonetheless, Buddhist Family members should take pride in being part of a cohesive and
          pioneering organization, unifying Vietnamese Buddhism and receiving accolades from devoted
          Buddhists nationwide. Why has the Buddhist Family Group long achieved such seamless unity? <footer>—Editorial
          Note</footer>
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <author>L.T.S.</author>
        <p>
          Out of gratitude for the compassionate Father sacrificing all to bring the light of truth
          for all beings;
        </p>
        <p>
          In sincere tribute to the mentors, brothers, and sisters who have given us and countless
          youths a vibrant life;
        </p>
        <p>
          Amid preparations for the Ten-Year Anniversary of the General Assembly of the Buddhist
          Family;
        </p>
        <p>
          I feel compelled to contribute something meaningful to our collective endeavor. This is
          the impetus behind my acceptance to compile this document at the Fourth General Assembly.
        </p>
        <p> Regarding content, the first section covers essential aspects of the Buddhist Family,
          since it is an organization with its management, outlined in the second part.
          Administration and operations rest upon leaders, whose lifestyles are reflected in the
          third part. These above parts exist due to the varying age groups involved. Classes vary
          by age and psychology, forming distinct ways of life, reason for the fourth part. Finally,
          as an organization, formalities are unavoidable; thus, the fifth part is equally
          important. Hence, the contents follow this structure: <ul>
            <li>Part I: Buddhist Family Group.</li>
            <li>Part II: Administration.</li>
            <li>Part III: Leadership.</li>
            <li>Part IV: Divisions.</li>
            <li>Part V: Formalities.</li>
          </ul> Each part is further subdivided for easy
          reference by leaders. To avoid dry repetition of resolutions from meetings, I infuse
          lively chapters, ideologies, either drawn from personal experiences, training camps, or
          studies. In terms of references, beyond charter, internal regulations, general assembly
          minutes, I curated additional details from: <ul>
            <li>The General Assembly President's speeches.</li>
            <li>Communications from Central Authority related to the Family Group.</li>
            <li>Works by Võ Đình Cường.</li>
            <li>Publications from Viên Âm.</li>
          </ul> Hence, I have accumulated during
          activities. </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection>
        <title>Conclusion</title>
        <p>
          Despite embodying ten years' experiences into this document, it cannot remain stationary.
          As “standing still” amidst time change equates regression, offending the World Honored
          One.
          Yet, this document, by karma law, is both the result of the past and the seed for the
          future.
          Vu Lan Season 2502
        </p>
        <author>Như Tâm NGUYỄN KHẮC TỪ</author>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <footnotes>
      <footnote number="1">Vu Lan: A significant Buddhist festival in Vietnam, also known as the
        Ghost Festival, honoring deceased ancestors.</footnote>
    </footnotes>
  </page>
  <page number="27">
    <section>
      <title>Part I: Buddhist Family Group</title>
      <subsection>
        <title>A. Overview of Buddhist Family Group</title>
        <p> The Buddhist Family Group isn’t a place for children to solely chant sutras for rituals
          or carry funeral banners. Nor is it intended to encourage neglect of schoolwork to
          organize meaningless games or unnecessary singing. <br />The Buddhist Family Group isn’t a
          youth organization with political objectives or a disguise. <br />The G.Đ.P.T. only
          borrows some methods from scouting. Yet, the spirit of youth remains rooted in Buddhism:
          Compassion, Wisdom, Diligence, Joy, Purity. <br />(Excerpt from "This Buddhist Family" by
          Võ Đình Cường) </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection>
        <title>I. Reasons for Establishment:</title>
        <p> If Buddhism is a path for all beings, it equally embraces youth. The Buddha guided La
          Hầu La alongside 500 children, accepted offerings from a child playing along the roadside,
          and delivered the Young Men’s Sutra, demonstrating Buddhism's special attention to the
          young. <br />The Buddhist Association comprises two layers: members and their children.
          It's essential to build genuine faith for future generations. </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </page>
  <page page="35">
    <p>An aim of the Association, especially as these children are living in a very complex era.
      These two causes are the driving force for the birth of the Gia Đình Phật Tử (Buddhist Family
      Group).</p>
    <title>II. ORIGINS AND EVOLUTIONARY PATH</title>
    <p>After supporting the modernization reform movement of Buddhism initiated by Ngài Thái Hư Đại
      Sư, the Vietnam Buddhist Association (then under the name An Nam Buddhist Association)
      immediately thought about the youth.</p>
    <p>In 1943, thanks to the initiative of <i>cư sĩ</i><footnote number="1">[1]</footnote> Tâm
      Minh, the Đức Dục Buddhist Study Group was born with the goal of training outstanding
      intellectuals to study and practice the teachings of Buddha. Gradually, under the guidance of
      its members, later organizations emerged:</p>
    <p>Youth Buddhists, Scout Buddhists, Child Buddhists, and the Buddhist Family Popularization
      Group. Youth Buddhists and Child Buddhists operated in urban areas, Scout Buddhists in rural
      areas, and the Buddhist Family Popularization Group for children in affluent families.</p>
    <p>After the return day (1947), the title "Buddhist Family Popularization Group" was raised, but
      its content had changed. The founders used the form of the Buddhist Family Popularization
      Group to avoid the scrutiny and prohibition of the authorities during the Vietnamese-French
      war; in reality, it was an organization of Youth, Adolescents, and Child Buddhists. However,
      the organization was still in its formative years, gaining experiences.</p>
    <p>Each group had a head called <i>Phổ trưởng</i>, and the children were <i>Phổ viên</i>. The
      group took the Dharma name of the <i>Phổ trưởng</i> or the local name.</p>
  </page>
  <footnotes>
    <footnote number="1">Cư sĩ refers to lay Buddhists who practice and support the teachings
      outside of monkhood.</footnote>
  </footnotes>
  <page page="36">
    <p>The Buddhist Family Popularization Group began to have a presence at Provincial Associations.
      Anh Võ Đình Cường was entrusted with leading the movement.</p>
    <p>A year later, the movement spread to the north and was welcomed by Buddhist collectives. The
      Minh Tâm Family in Hanoi and the Liên Hoa Family in Hai Phong were the first two families in
      Northern Vietnam.</p>
    <p>In 1951, to unify the organization, the Grand Council convened a conference on April 24-25-26
      at Từ Đàm Pagoda in Huế. The conference included eight provinces in Central Vietnam and
      representatives from Northern Vietnam G.Đ.P.T. Once again, the conference changed the title to
      "GIA ĐÌNH PHẬT TỬ" (Buddhist Family). The Bylaws were also outlined at this conference.</p>
    <p>In 1953, notably, this conference echoed with voices from North, Central, and South Vietnam
      through the participation of 63 delegates representing the three regions. The conference's
      main goal was to find methods to "improve the life of G.Đ.P.T." with three slogans:</p>
    <ol>
      <li>Religion in life, life in religion.</li>
      <li>Theory for practice, practice for theory.</li>
      <li>Timely and suitable application.</li>
    </ol>
    <p>The heartfelt call of anh Trưởng ban Hướng dẫn Tổng hội... "For the noble ideal of G.Đ.P.T.,
      we will not refuse any toil or suffering. Under our care are thousands of youths entrusted by
      parents for us to guide, protect, and nurture. The elite elements of Buddhist youth and the
      country are entrusting their lives to us. We must be worthy of that mission..." led to the
      result: in just four days (January 1-4, 1951). The conference completed a study program for
      various sectors, a considerable undertaking worth remembering.</p>
  </page>

  <page page="37">
    <p>The call for unity of North, Central, and South was sparked from this conference.</p>
    <p>In 1955, the third conference took place at Linh Sơn Pagoda in Đà Lạt, from July 31 to August
      3, 1958. This time, many delegates from Southern Vietnam provinces participated, bearing the
      weight as described by anh T.B.H.D. of Southern Vietnam...</p>
  </page>

  <page page="38">
    <title>THE LONG-TERM REPORT PRICE</title>
    <p>(To be continued)</p>
    <p>3 months</p>
    <p>6 months: 30đ.00</p>
    <p>55đ.00</p>
    <p>1 year: 110đ.00</p>
    <p>Retail price per issue: 10 đồng. The editorial office still has complete issues from number 1
      to 23.</p>
    <p>From numbers 1 to 12 bound in a volume, hard cover, gold lettering, priced at 140 đồng (extra
      20 đồng for distant shipping charges).</p>
    <p>Contributions, articles should be sent to the Editorial Office: 243 Đường Sư Vạn Hạnh Cholon.</p>
    <p>Money orders, payable to: Nguyễn Văn Nhã, Manager.</p>
    <p>A temple made of marble in Thailand. Inside, visitors will see the most artistic bronze and
      stone Buddha statues in the world.</p>
  </page>

  <page page="39">
    <title>SEEKING TRUTH</title>
    <author>Đức Cương Nguyễn</author>
    <p>This is a literary competition essay organized by the magazine; it has value, but
      unfortunately, it arrived too late for submission, so we had to classify it as invalid. To
      console the author and introduce a meaningful work to our readers, depicted with a skillful
      pen, we publish the essay "Seeking Truth" below.</p>
    <i>L. T. S.</i>
    <p>In olden days, there was a young man burdened with deep sorrow about life, who set out one
      morning on a quest for Truth.</p>
    <p>He heard that in a certain temple, there was a true practitioner, an ascetic who had mastered
      many miraculous skills and understood the subtle and mysterious truths of the universe, so he
      decided to seek this teacher for guidance. The journey was fraught with challenges, but with
      unwavering determination, he ignored all perils. From afar, one day, the Sacred Temple loomed
      before him, majestic and resplendent. His young heart bubbled with elation.</p>
    <p>He found his way to the sage's private chamber, fell to his knees: "Master, this humble
      seeker has long admired your revered reputation, believing in the miraculous proficiency of
      the path, hence traveling thousands of miles to beseech you to show me the way to seek the
      Truth."</p>
    <p>The sage replied:</p>
    <p>"The temple doors are not narrow to anyone, its heart open to all. The path to Truth begins
      from the Sacred Temple, for Truth must...</p>
  </page>

  <page page="40">
    <p>...be discovered through the tranquility of the soul, through reverent, trusting intellect.
      From here to the pinnacle of the temple, the path has three levels: the first level of
      asceticism, the second level of selflessness, the third level of love. These three levels
      teach that: Without diligent effort to endure life's hardships for understanding, without
      shedding personal biases to objectively view things, without deep compassion demanding Truth,
      one will never discover Truth. Truth or Reality belongs to everyone but must be sought by
      traveling these three levels."</p>
    <p>The young man felt indescribable joy and hastily asked:</p>
    <p>"Master, so Truth lies at the temple's pinnacle?"</p>
    <p>The sage gently replied:</p>
    <p>"Indeed. I am certain that at the ultimate end of the three levels, atop the Sacred Temple is
      the statue of the god of Truth. What it looks like, I cannot say, as I have only traversed the
      path of asceticism and completed the level of selflessness. The second level is the most
      challenging because discarding personal biases is excessively arduous for us. Only the final
      segment remains, the segment of love, whereupon one will behold the plethora of Truth's
      splendor, but the path of love is both near and far, as often humans confuse self-love with
      love for others, so only thirty steps remain but I am still stagnant."</p>
    <p>The sage continued:</p>
    <p>"Currently, the temple houses countless seekers. Some have completed the first level, others
      are stepping onto the second, some are laboring from the start, and countless have retreated,
      returning home, abandoning the quest for Truth because their hearts lacked the passion to bear
      the challenges. The temple's doors remain ever open, seek your path."</p>
    <p>From then, the young man began his studies. He embarked on the path of asceticism to
      empathize with the world's suffering. From then on, everything around him seemed changed. The
      cries and laughter, the tears and smiles were tinged with a strange newness. He no longer
      engaged with things superficially. He perceived the breadth, depth, and height of each sound,
      feeling seemingly ever closer to humanity each day.</p>
    <p>Yet, each morning glancing at the temple's summit, he felt the journey impossibly distant.
      His mind unsettled, the path, short as it was, felt infinitely extended. He observed the
      separating walls, the steep ascendant steps and desired to shorten the journey. One night, he
      conceived an idea.</p>
    <p>One cold moonlit night, he used a vine to climb over the wall. Acquainted with physical
      exercise since youth, it took little effort to surpass the thick, rugged walls. Ascending
      higher, looking back down, he felt he had performed a remarkable feat. When he reached the
      temple's summit, the moon had set, casting his large shadow on the stone wall like a giant
      figure; he felt detached from humanity and superior to everything. He thought, "Finding Truth
      does not solely rely on the three levels path. With intelligence, courage, and resolute
      determination, I can reach Truth more swiftly than anyone."</p>
    <p>He then entered the temple, the site of the god of Truth's statue. He ventured in the dead of
      night, through silent heights, traversing wind-chilled corridors, seeing only his lonely
      shadow trailing and hearing only his own footsteps echoing with peculiar resonances.</p>
    <p>He ventured further inward, sensing the heavy silence with each step. As the late night moon
      crumbled outside, he felt a chill, but his pride in his feat urged him to suppress all
      apprehensions. He thought, "Now it is only me and Truth."</p>
    <p>The statue of the god of Truth lay behind that door. He approached, mustering all courage to
      push the door. Suddenly, he screamed, clutching his face, and like a man pursued by the dead,
      he fled from the temple in panic, crashing into stone pillars, stumbling on the threshold,
      falling flat on the brick floor, yet terror overwhelmed him to the point of desperately
      escaping.</p>
    <p>Clinging onto the wall, finding the vine, he hastily scrambled down. In his haste, he fell
      from the high wall to the temple's foot.</p>
    <p>The next morning, at the temple's base, people found his body cold and rigid, his face still
      contorted with extreme horror.</p>
    <p>The sage pensively gazed at the body, then turned to his students:</p>
    <footer>"Here is one who did not seek Truth through the proper path. He followed a deceitful
      path, believing it swifter, thinking only his talents could lead him to it. He forgot that his
      heart was the core of seeking this Truth.</footer>
  </page>

  <page page="41">
    <p>When the heart is correct, talents turn into achievements and glorious victories. When the
      heart is misguided, talents are mere schemes, base tactics. The outcome he encountered was a
      ghastly Truth so horrific he ended his own life. Remember, beautiful Truth, Truth comforting
      and uplifting humanity can only be reached through the threefold path: the path of asceticism,
      the path of selflessness, and the path of love. Whoever doesn't follow this path but resorts
      to deceit, coercion, or corruption will destroy not only themselves but even entire systems."</p>
    <p>The sage paused briefly and then gently continued:</p>
    <p>"I have long reminded you of this, and now here is tangible evidence. Bury him at the
      temple's entrance and inscribe on his grave the horror-stricken face of one who sought Truth
      via a wayward path, serving as a caution to others."</p>
    <title>Mr. Thuần Đà Invites the Buddha</title>
    <p>Arriving at the city of Ba-Ba, the Buddha and the Sangha rested in Mr. Thuần Đà's garden.</p>
    <p>Mr. Thuần Đà and his comrades came to pay homage and inquire about the visit. The Buddha
      said:</p>
    <p>"I am about to enter <i>Niết-bàn</i><footnote number="1">[1]</footnote>, so I wish to come
      here for a meeting."</p>
    <p>Upon hearing this, Mr. Thuần Đà and everyone lamented, imploring the Buddha to stay in the
      world. The Buddha comforted them as He did with others.</p>
    <p>Subsequently, he invited the Buddha and the Sangha to his home for meals the next day. The
      Buddha was silent. After the meal, the Buddha told Mr. Thuần Đà:</p>
    <p>"Now you have accomplished the rare merit of offering food to the Buddha and Sangha for the
      last time. This merit will never be exhausted. The merits accrued by all beings cannot compare
      with yours. You should rejoice. This is the last invitation I will accept from you!"</p>
    <p>(According to the Great Nirvana Sutra)</p>
  </page>
  <footnotes>
    <footnote number="1">Niết-bàn is the Vietnamese transliteration of the Sanskrit word "Nirvana,"
      which refers to the ultimate spiritual goal in Buddhism, a transcendent state free from
      suffering and the cycle of birth and rebirth.</footnote>
  </footnotes>

  <page page="42">
    <title>Nữ Đạo Hữu Marguerite La Fuente Has Passed Away</title>
    <p>The Buddhist Society of France, along with friends of worldwide Buddhist followers, was
      suddenly informed: Layperson Marguerite La Fuente, author, and translator of numerous books on
      Buddhism, passed away in Paris on June 7, 1958.</p>
    <p>Marguerite was born in Saint-Germain-en-Laye on October 23, 1887. She hailed from an
      aristocratic Spanish family that settled in Franche-Comté during King Louis XIV's reign.</p>
    <p>Her father was a polymath. Her mother was of French origin. As a child, she traveled with her
      father to Constantinople. She returned to France at 12. When World War I erupted in 1914-1918,
      she joined the ambulance corps. Shortly thereafter, she established a bookstore aimed at
      helping young writers and artists advance, but the venture went bankrupt. In 1929, she joined
      the "Friends of Buddhism" society established by Thái Hư Pháp Sư and his disciple Lounsberry.
      From then on, a new life began: La Fuente diligently dedicated herself to serving Buddhism.
      She translated numerous Buddhist texts and wrote articles for the magazine La Pensée
      Bouddhique. Until her life's final moments, she was surrounded by Buddhist books, her most
      cherished companions in her vibrant life.</p>
    <p>Seven days after her passing, a prayer service was organized. The ceremony was simple, yet
      its atmosphere was immensely solemn. Four venerables from Cambodia and Thailand attended.
      Moreover, representatives from Asian Buddhist nations were sent. Notable attendees included
      Mr. U Ba Yi of the Myanmar Consulate, Mr. Poe Thieun of the Cambodian Embassy, Prince
      Norindeth, Mr. Cunasekera, Minister of Sri Lanka, and entourage, Mr. Pendsay, Ambassador of
      India, Mr. Enthri Bijayendrayodhin, Ambassador of Sri Lanka, and numerous representatives from
      other countries.</p>
    <p>During this occasion, Dr. Rahula, a collaborator with Marguerite in translating Buddhist
      texts, delivered a short speech praising her brilliant mind. He recounted that a day before
      her passing, she was still diligently translating texts from her bed. When he visited her, she
      entrusted him with comparing the original Pali texts to her translations.</p>
    <p>The president of the French Buddhist society, with touching words, shared that for 25 years
      of collaboration, La Fuente truly followed Buddhism's path in action and thought. Her passing
      is a great loss to French Buddhism, a strong member has departed, and to the Buddhist world, a
      valuable talent in propagating and spreading Buddhism in Western Europe.</p>
  </page>

  <page page="43">
    <title>NEWS</title>
    <p>This year's Vesak festival was celebrated with grandeur across various countries. In London,
      the Burmese Ambassador Mr. U. Aung Soe raised Buddhist flags, heralding a three-day festival,
      marking a new chapter in the history of Buddhism in the West. Venerable Sayadaw U Thittila
      Aggamahapandita, who had significantly contributed to Buddhism in England for 14 years,
      recounted the life of the Buddha and highlighted the path of salvation of the Blessed One. Mr.
      Ganasena de Soysa, the Sri Lankan High Commissioner, appreciated the presence of ambassadors
      from Myanmar, Thailand, Cambodia, and Laos at this celebration, emphasizing Buddhism as an
      element of peace for humanity.</p>
    <p>The sixth Vesak festival in Washington D.C. concluded successfully. It is believed to be the
      first convergence of Eastern teachings with the Western scientific spirit. As the Buddha
      statue was unveiled, Dr. Leidecker explained that this gift symbolizes the hope of Thai
      Buddhism for a cordial relationship between the Thai and American peoples.</p>
    <p>The plan to build a monastery was actively discussed by ambassadors from Buddhist countries
      at the Burmese and Sri Lankan embassies.</p>
    <p>Ten Buddhist countries in Asia offered a sum of 3,000,000 đồng: Myanmar, Cambodia, Sri Lanka,
      India, Laos, Thailand, Vietnam, Korea, Taiwan, and Japan... These countries comprise about
      500,000,000 Buddhist followers.</p>
    <p>American Buddhist friends involved in the monastery's construction include Professor Kurt F.
      Leidecker, a Virginia University professor, Colonel Seaborne of the U.S. Army, and Mr. William
      Schlecht, chairman of the Friends of Buddhism association.</p>
    <p>Thai Buddhism donated a Buddha statue, displayed during the Vesak celebrations in Washington
      D.C.</p>
  </page>

  <page page="44">
    <p>This year's Vesak festival in Paris spanned two days. As in previous years, the Thai
      ambassador in Paris organized the event. A stone Buddha statue, an art masterpiece from
      Cambodia, was placed on the altar.</p>
    <p>Surrounding the statue was an array of white flowers symbolizing perfect peace. Two renowned
      venerables attended the ceremony: The representative of Bra Gru Sanghasattha Phonn Sompheach
      Dhammarama who recently arrived from Cambodia, and Venerable Rahula, who has been present in
      Paris for seven years, together with ambassadors from Thailand, and Sri Lanka who recently
      took office in Paris, Cambodian diplomatic missions, Professor Jean Filliozal... Apart from
      regular rituals, this year's Vesak festival featured numerous films about Buddhism, beneficial
      for propagating it. Attendees witnessed Buddhist festivals in Thailand, pilgrimages in Sri
      Lanka, and various mysterious scenes from Indian movies about the Buddha.</p>
    <p>The historical World's Religious Congress this year was grandly held at the Sankei Hall Union
      in Tokyo (Japan) for nearly two weeks from August 27 to September 9, 1958.</p>
    <p>This conference aimed to exchange knowledge, thoughts, and scholarship on world religions
      with the purpose of enhancing understanding and fostering friendship among world religions,
      not engaging in politics, as political issues were not addressed.</p>
    <p>Numerous eminent scholars and adherents from various religions attended. Nearly 200
      representatives from about 30 countries participated, alongside over 500 Japanese religious
      representatives. Delegates from Britain, France, the U.S., Germany, the Netherlands, Italy,
      India, the Union, Sri Lanka, the Philippines, Indonesia, China, Japan, and Vietnam, among
      others, attended.</p>
    <p>Thượng tọa Visiddhananda, head of the Buddhist Association of the Union, noted that the
      Government of the Islamic Republic provides an annual incentive of 30,000 rupees to encourage
      Buddhist education in the Union.</p>
    <p>The Eastern Holy Government also offers a subsidy exceeding 30,000 rupees for the same
      purpose.</p>
    <p>During a visit to Bodhgaya, Myanmar's Prime Minister, Mr. Unu, proclaimed that today's
      development of Bodhgaya is due to India's efforts. Prime Minister Unu donated 10,000 rupees to
      the Bodhgaya restoration committee. His total contribution to Bodhgaya's expansion now amounts
      to 30,000 rupees (about 300,000 Vietnamese đồng).</p>
  </page>

  <page page="45">
    <p>At 3 PM on Sunday, October 5, 1958, the Southern Vietnam Sangha reopened the Basic Buddhist
      Studies class at the Southern Vietnam Buddhist school, Ấn Quang Temple, 243 Sư Bạn Hạnh
      Street, Chợ Lớn, under the instruction of Thầy lecturers Thích Huyền Vi and Thích Thiền Định.</p>
    <p>And at 7 PM that evening, Thượng tọa Thích Thiện Hoa continued lecturing on the <i>Viên Giác</i>
      Sutra and the <i>Nhân Minh Luận</i>.</p>
    <p>Responding to social endeavors, Thượng tọa Trí Dũng of Phổ Quang Temple in Northern Vietnam's
      cemetery established a social committee to aid impoverished fellow citizens with deceased
      relatives. The Phổ Quang Temple's social committee will provide funeral vehicles, coffins,
      burial shrouds, and burial land.</p>
    <p>According to the meeting on September 4, 1958, under the chairmanship of Hòa thượng Pháp chủ
      G.H.T.G.T.P., the third General Council session was decided to be held on August 26-27-28 of
      the lunar year Mậu Tuất, corresponding to October 8-9-10, 1958, at the Southern Vietnam
      Sangha's headquarters, Linh Quang Pagoda, Huế.</p>
    <p>The General Council is composed of venerable Hòa thượng elders, venerable Thượng tọa, and 30
      members appointed by provincial administrative committees and some monks invited by the Tông
      Trị Sự to attend.</p>
    <p>At 8 AM on October 14, 1958, there was a special film screening organized by the Sangha
      Temple at Đại Nam Theater, Trần Hưng Đạo Street, Sài Gòn. The film screening aimed to build
      the "Phật Học Ni Trường Tăng Già" at Vĩnh Hội Sài Gòn's Sangha Temple.</p>
    <p>The film screened was the tale of Trần Huyền Trang's renunciation (or Three Treasures'
      renunciation), a moral film extolling the Buddhist law of karma. Those who do good are
      protected by the Buddha, and those who do evil must pay for their misdeeds.</p>
  </page>

  <page page="46">
    <title>Answer Key to Recreational Contest No. 22</title>
    <p>First question: Emperor Lý Thái Tổ, also known as Lý Công Uẩn, originated from the monastery
      before becoming emperor.</p>
    <p>Emperor Trần Nhân Tông abdicated the throne and became a monk, founding the "Trúc Lâm Yên Tử"
      sect.</p>
    <p>Second question: Từ Đàm Pagoda was established in 1683 by Minh Hoàng Tử Dung.</p>
    <p>The pagoda witnessed a significant event in Vietnamese Buddhist history: the conference of 51
      Buddhist delegates from Central, North, and South Vietnam in 1951 to unify Vietnamese
      Buddhism.</p>
    <p>Third question: 11 individuals answered correctly.</p>
    <title>RESULTS</title>
    <p>First: Trần Văn Ninh, Dharma name Nguyên Tịnh, Hỏa Xa Office Quy Nhơn.</p>
    <p>Second: Nguyễn Minh Hoàng, 27 K Nguyễn An Ninh Gia Định.</p>
    <p>Third: Huỳnh Bá Yết Dương, 279/6 Phan Đình Phùng Đà Lạt.</p>
    <p>Fourth: Nguyễn Như Danh, 3 Lê Huân inside Huế citadel.</p>
    <p>Fifth: Nguyễn Phương Hạnh, female student, 37 Hùng Vương Boulevard, Mỹ Tho.</p>
    <p>Prizes will be sent promptly to the winners.</p>
    <title>RECREATIONAL CONTEST NO. 24</title>
    <i>P. G. V. N.</i>
    <p>Why has Vietnamese Buddhism not yet achieved true unification?</p>
    <p>Please propose methods to remedy the above situation.</p>
  </page>

  <page page="47">
    <title>EDITORIAL OFFICE MAILBOX</title>
    <p>Mr. Đặng Quốc Toản. (K.B.C. 4093)</p>
    <ol>
      <li>Regarding the P.G.V.N. decorations article, please send it to the address: 243 Sư Vạn Hạnh
        Cholon.</li>
      <li>The newspaper no longer has space to publish that section. Please send samples of
        collections that could bring some benefit to readers.</li>
      <li>The editorial office is attentive to this matter. Rest assured.</li>
    </ol>
    <p>Young Ms. Văn Hoa (Mỹ Tho). Like other magazines, the Editorial Office is always considering
      supporting readers with a love for literature who wish to submit their creations to the
      Editorial Office.</p>
    <p>Ms. Hoàng Thị Huyền (Bến Tre). Delighted to receive your encouragement. P.G.V.N. constantly
      strives to make the newspaper newer every day.</p>
    <p>Mr. Nguyễn Hữu Văn (Hà Tiên) The Editorial Office has long considered your suggestion. If
      convenient, there will be a reader poll on this matter. Thank you.</p>
    <p>Professor Văn Hoàng (Sài Gòn) Thank you for your sincere encouragement. Besides the content
      of the articles, the Editorial Office considers this matter important. We hope future issues
      will be even more perfect, as we consider not only the content of the articles but also
      spelling on newspaper pages as matters requiring the Editorial Office's attention.</p>
    <p>Many readers: Teacher Minh Hạnh remains the editor of P.C.V.N; his health has improved
      somewhat. He expresses gratitude to all patrons concerned about his health.</p>
    <p>Lay member Tâm Hỷ: To meet, please contact Teacher Từ Mẫn directly at the Editorial Office.
      M.H.</p>
    <p>Mr. Hoàng Quang Doãn: Payment for newspapers can be made with stamps. For newspaper
      subscriptions, please pay in advance. Please send that amount to the Management Department.</p>
    <p>Mr. Minh Tử: We will wait for P.G.V.N. issue 24 to be completed, then send it to you. Please
      be patient.</p>
    <p>Mr. Nguyễn An (Quảng Trị): Subscription information is noted in every newspaper issue. Kindly
      refer back to it. Farewell.</p>
    <p>Lay members Tâm Hiền and Minh Quang: Articles "Recognizing and Realizing," "Buddhist Study
      Method"... Unfortunately, we cannot publish them because P.G.V.N. is not a forum for debate.</p>
    <p>Mr. Hiền Đức: "Huyền Trang's Footsteps" will be published in the next issue. Congratulations.</p>
    <p>Teacher Thích Tâm Thọ: It will be published. Please look forward to reading it in the next
      issue.</p>
    <p>Friends: Trần Công Lý and Lê Thiện Tuế: Received your works. Reviewing them currently.</p>
    <p>Lay member Trần Hữu Nhơn: Your letter has been received.</p>
    <p>"The one who gives receives merit,</p>
    <p>The compassionate one bears no grievance;</p>
    <p>The one who acts benevolently avoids evil,</p>
    <p>The one without desires is free from distress.</p>
    <p>If such virtues are practiced,</p>
    <p>One quickly attains Nirvana."</p>
    <p>This is the verse spoken by the Blessed One to Mr. Thuần Đà before His passing.</p>
  </page>

  <page page="48" />
  <page page="49" />
  <page page="50" />
  <page page="51" />
</document>